# Vootla Chaitanya

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India



chaitanyavootla@proton.me



linkedin.com/in/vootlachaitanya

## **Summary**

I'm a Computer Science and Engineering student from NIT Agartala with experience in Nodejs, Vue.js, Angular, SQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Kubernetes and Docker. Over the course of my career I've created and overhauled features spanning from UI to API to microservices working with multiple teams across multiple time zones.

Currently creating the next big CI/CD tool https://jfrog.com/pipelines

## **Experience**

## **Software Developer**

**JFrog** 

Apr 2019 - Present (4 years)

- Implemented several features core to the CI/CD platform spanning from cloud orchestration to micro services to optimization across the board and constantly improving reliability and smoothness of the product https://jfrog.com/pipelines
- Built the UI from scratch and related backend
- Worked extensively on real-time data visualization using d3js and canvas, client and server side performance optimization
- Worked closely with multiple teams across 3 time-zones on recognizing customer commitments, product design and UX

Current stack: Nodejs, Javascript, Vue.js, postgres, Jest and cypress

## Software Developer

Shippable

Jun 2016 - Mar 2019 (2 years 10 months)

- Built the most versatile CI/CD platform(Shippable), created and overhauled features spanning from UI to API to microservices
- Owned and created many features like historic insights, graph visualization, worked closely with product team to flesh out and fine tune features
- Worked with the company until it successfully got acquired by the market leader (JFrog)

Stack: Javascript, Angularis, Nodeis, MongoDB, Postgres



#### Intern

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

May 2015 - Jul 2015 (3 months)

Completed an unfinished project in which ultrasound is used to recognize gestures using signal analysis and machine learning in mobile devices.

#### **Education**

### National Institute of Technology Agartala

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science And Engineering 2012 - 2016 7.38

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



NTPEL course on programming, algorithms and data structures - NPTEL



NTPEL course on introduction to c - NPTEL



**DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization** - Coursera 3MP7PXK3YVH6



TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques Specialization - Coursera **CTWUCLAZDZPP** 

#### **Skills**

Node is · AngularJS · PostgreSQL · Android Development · Docker · PHP · C · MongoDB · C++ • Java

#### **Honors & Awards**



National 39th rank in NPTEL's introduction to programming in c course - NPTEL

Feb 2015

Featured in top scorers page in NPTEL's introduction to programming in c course for securing 99% score

link to the page: https://nptel.ac.in/noc/courses/noc14/SEM2/noc14-cs02/